WILMAR A. STEPHENS

New York, NY, 10037

Phone: 212-353-1241 | Email: wilmars@alumni.brown.edu LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wilmars | GitHub: https://github.com/wilmararturo Portfolio: https://wilmararturo.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

DevOps Engineer and Full Stack Web Developer with experience working in public and private cloud environments including VMware. Azure, and AWS. Committed to building repeatable and shareable infrastructure, applications, and processes. Management experience and ITIL certification.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Powershell, Python, HCL

Applications: Ansible, Terraform, Packer, Docker, Jira, Confluence, Jenkins, SQL Server

AWS: S3, Cloudfront, Route53, EC2, ECS, Lambda, DynamoDB

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MacOS

PROJECTS

Covid Alert | https://github.com/wilmararturo/covid-alert | https://wilmararturo.github.io/covid-alert/

- Application to see state level data on Covid-19 cased, deaths, and recoveries
- Build chart and search button
- Manage issues and Kanban board
- Javascript, ¡Query, ChartJS, Bootstrap, CSS, Public Data API

Weather Dashboard | https://github.com/wilmararturo/weather-dashboard | https://wilmararturo.github.io/weather-dashboard/

- Application to get current conditions and forecast for a selected city
- Build and deploy application
- Javascript, ¡Query, Openweather API Bootstrap, CSS

Code Quiz | https://github.com/wilmararturo/code-quiz | https://wilmararturo.github.io/code-quiz/

- Simple quiz of basic Javascript concepts.
- Build and deploy application
- Javascript, Bootstrap, CSS

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer Equinox

2017 – Present New York, NY

DevOps Engineer building shareable and repeatable infrastructure using infrastructure as code and employing devops practices. Work with local and offshore teams to add automation, resilience, and reliability to cloud based environments.

Key Accomplishments:

- Introduce Terraform as the primary infrastructure as code software.
- Automate Jenkins infrastructure
- Establish process for deploying Microsoft SQL Servers with consistent configurations using Packer, Terraform, and Ansible

TT Manager 2014 – 2017 Outbrain New York, NY

Managed the US based IT team. Worked with the global IT team on tool selection, IT processes and procedures. Functioned as the lead system administrator for ServiceNow. Developed integrations between ServiceNow and other solutions including JAMF Casper, Dell Kace, OpenLDAP, and Jira.

Key Accomplishments:

- Built processes in ServiceNow to facilitate coordination between HR and IT for onboarding.
- Managed IT for office relocations and renovations
- Built custom applications and integrations in ServiceNow for Business Intelligence and Information Systems teams.

Window System Engineer Ideeli, Inc

2012 - 2014

New York, NY

Windows System Engineer responsible for maintaining Windows Server infrastructure. Worked with the finance, accounting, and merchandising team to support the Epicor ERP systems including application servers, client servers, and database backend.

Key Accomplishments:

- Built custom monitoring to notify of issues with the ERP system.
- Documented policies and procedures around the Epicor ERP system including custom third party integrations.
- Planned and implemented the major lift and shift of Windows infrastructure between cloud providers.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: Columbia University, New York, NY

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Sciense. Biochemistry: Brown University, Providence, RI